<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Case of those persons that have purchased soldiers arrears, the Irish transport debt, salt tallies, malt tickets, or an interest in any other deficient funds</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A78278</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1190B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224815</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45097615</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45097615</idno>
            <idno type="VID">171222</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A78278)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 171222)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2568:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Case of those persons that have purchased soldiers arrears, the Irish transport debt, salt tallies, malt tickets, or an interest in any other deficient funds</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Sutro Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Speculation --  England.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:171222:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The CASE of thoſe Perſons that have Purchaſed Soldiers <hi>Arrears,</hi> the <hi>Iriſh Tranſport Debt, Salt Tal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies, Malt Tickets,</hi> or an Intereſt in any other De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient Funds.</head>
            <p>A good or bad Title enhances or debaſes the Purchaſe of any Commodity, is well known to any Man that ever bought a Foot of Land upon a controverted or diſputed Right.</p>
            <p>If the Hazard bear a proportion to the Gain, 'tis a Juſt and Righteous Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain; I am ſure it appear'd ſo to the Wiſdom of <hi>The Honourable Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons,</hi> when for Ten Pounds they allow'd a Chance of Thouſand Pounds <hi>per Annum,</hi> as in <hi>The Million Lottery,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>That this is the Caſe of thoſe Perſons that have bought Arrears, may appear from hence:</p>
            <p>They were eſteem'd both by the Buyer and Seller to be unſettl'd and preca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious Things, not likely to be paid of a long time, eſpecially if the War had laſted, or broke out a-new, carried no Intereſt, by the Sale of them, there was no Right veſted in, or transfer'd to the Purchaſer, as in <hi>Salt-Tallies,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Many of the Officers that ſold their Arrears bought Places with the Purchaſe Money, without which they would probably have Starved before they could have been Reliev'd by a Parliamentary Proviſion; and all thoſe Gentlemen that ſold their Pay, hired Brokers and Sollicitors to find them Chapmen.</p>
            <p>Many of thoſe that bought Soldiers Arrears, Malt-Tickets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> took their Money out of the <hi>Bank</hi> and other Funds in order to make a better Purchaſe, and conſequently, will be the greater looſers if this Clauſe be admitted.</p>
            <p>What Proviſion would the <hi>Honourable Houſe</hi> have made to Re-imburſe the Purchaſers, in Caſe the Arrears had never been paid?</p>
            <p>Where Officers ſold their Pay two or three times over, what Proviſion ſhall be made for the ſecond or third Purchaſer? <hi>Caveat Emptor</hi> is the common An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, then let him have a better Bargain for the great Riſque he runs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>When <hi>Salt Tallies</hi> have been ſold ſometimes at <hi>Cent per Cent</hi> loſs, <hi>Bank Bills, Chequer Notes, Malt Tickets,</hi> at a very great Diſcount, tho' they had eſtabliſh'd Funds, and a growing Intereſt on them, why are not thoſe Bargains reſcinded, and all other unequal Contracts, and where will the <hi>Houſe</hi> Begin or End?</p>
            <p>If it be a Crime to take more than common Intereſt upon ſome occaſions, or to Buy a great Bargain, why has <hi>The Honourable Houſe</hi> encouraged it all the laſt War, and ſince; witneſs the great Premiums and the large Intereſts allow'd upon the ſafeſt Funds, witneſs a Clauſe in a certain Act made laſt Seſſions, whereby the Commiſſioners of the Victualling, were empower'd to pay away <hi>Malt Tickets,</hi> and <hi>Coal Tallies</hi> which carried Eight <hi>per Cent</hi> Intereſt at a conſider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able diſcount both of Intereſt and Principle.</p>
            <p>It is humbly propoſed that this Matter ought to be decided in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall,</hi> if there be any Law that makes ſuch Contracts Criminal, if there be no Law, there is no Tranſgreſſion.</p>
            <p>It is humbly ſubmitted to the Conſideration of the <hi>Houſe,</hi> that not one of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Officers that ſold his Arrears, was a Minor or a <hi>Non Compos,</hi> nor one <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:171222:2"/>
            <p> Many of the Officers that ſold their Arrears bought Places with the Purchaſe Money, without which they would probably have Starved before they could have been Reliev'd by a Parliamentary Proviſion; and all thoſe Gentlemen that ſold their Pay, hired Brokers and Sollicitors to find them Chapmen.</p>
            <p>Many of thoſe that bought Soldiers Arrears, Malt-Tickets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> took their Money out of the <hi>Bank</hi> and other Funds in order to make a better Purchaſe, and conſequently, will be the greater looſers if this Clauſe be admitted.</p>
            <p>What Proviſion would the <hi>Honourable Houſe</hi> have made to Re-imburſe the Purchaſers, in Caſe the Arrears had never been paid?</p>
            <p>Where Officers ſold their Pay two or three times over, what Proviſion ſhall be made for the ſecond or third Purchaſer? <hi>Caveat Emptor</hi> is the common An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, then let him have a better Bargain for the great Riſque he runs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>When <hi>Salt Tallies</hi> have been ſold ſometimes at <hi>Cent per Cent</hi> loſs, <hi>Bank Bills, Chequer Notes, Malt Tickets,</hi> at a very great Diſcount, tho' they had eſtabliſh'd Funds, and a growing Intereſt on them, why are not thoſe Bargains reſcinded, and all other unequal Contracts, and where will the <hi>Houſe</hi> Begin or End?</p>
            <p>If it be a Crime to take more than common Intereſt upon ſome occaſions, or to Buy a great Bargain, why has <hi>The Honourable Houſe</hi> encouraged it all the laſt War, and ſince; witneſs the great Premiums and the large Intereſts allow'd upon the ſafeſt Funds, witneſs a Clauſe in a certain Act made laſt Seſſions, whereby the Commiſſioners of the Victualling, were empower'd to pay away <hi>Malt Tickets,</hi> and <hi>Coal Tallies</hi> which carried Eight <hi>per Cent</hi> Intereſt at a conſider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able diſcount both of Intereſt and Principle.</p>
            <p>It is humbly propoſed that this Matter ought to be decided in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall,</hi> if there be any Law that makes ſuch Contracts Criminal, if there be no Law, there is no Tranſgreſſion.</p>
            <p>It is humbly ſubmitted to the Conſideration of the <hi>Houſe,</hi> that not one of the Officers that ſold his Arrears, was a Minor or a <hi>Non Compos,</hi> nor one of the Buyers extorted ſuch a Sale, or reduced the Seller to any ſtreights or neceſſities in order to make an advantage thereby.</p>
            <p>Where the value of any Commodity riſes or falls by a bear Rumor, as <hi>Tallies</hi> and <hi>Stocks</hi> have done by the report of the King of <hi>Spain</hi>'s Death; ſuch Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities can never be worth ſo much as others of laſting unchangeable value.</p>
            <p>If notwithſtanding what has been objected againſt in this Clauſe <hi>The Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Houſe</hi> I ſhall incline to reſcind theſe Bargins, it is humbly hoped that they will fix a ſhort Day whereby thoſe Officers who have ſold upon payment of the Money in <hi>Specie</hi> by them received, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and intereſt for the ſame at the rate of <hi>— per Cent</hi> may have the benefit of the Act, otherwiſe to be for ever forecloſed.</p>
            <p>Laſtly, If all legal Contracts and Bargins be not preſerved ſacred and inviolable, it is humbly ſubmitted to the Wiſdom of <hi>The Honourable Houſe,</hi> whither upon any great Exigence it would be poſſible to raiſe again thoſe mighty Sums, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out which the Nation could never have carried on, nor ſo gloriouſly have en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded the late War with <hi>France.</hi> Many Officers who ſold their Arrears were Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reigners, and parted with them to raiſe Money to pay the Fees for their Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turalization, which if they had not done, they could neither have continued in the Service or been intituled to half Pay.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
